ROISIN YATES | FULL STACK DEVELOPER

New Zealand citizen

roisinyatesdev@outlook.com | 0204 138 3787

LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

ABOUT ME

I am a versatile and creative Full Stack Web Developer with a particular interest in using React and Typescript to design and implement intuitive and user-friendly systems.

With 2+ years of retail experience and background in Ancient Art History and Civilisation, I bring unique and valuable insight to every project I take on. My previous research of Bronze Age rituals has provided me with a deep understanding of the importance of storytelling in design, as well as a critical perspective on diverse needs and viewpoints of different groups.

EXPERIENCE

TRAINEE | DEV ACADEMY AOTEAROA

01/2023 - 05/2023

- A 15-week immersive, full-stack web development bootcamp, where we applied agile
 methodologies to simulate real-world engineering teams, and build group projects. Throughout
 the program, I honed my technical skills in technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, Typescript,
 JavaScript, React, Redux, Knex, SQLite3, Node.js, and Express.js.
- There was significant emphasis placed on Human Skills, through which we deepened our understanding of Non-Violent Communication, communication, empathy and wellbeing.
- Each week, we worked in pairs, or groups, to deliver full-stack projects, including my final project, <u>SubMinder</u>: A subscription tracking app which allowed you to create, edit and delete paid subscriptions and free trials.
- I was the **product owner** of SubMinder, and led our team of six. I gained valuable project management skills, such as **setting the minimum viable product (MVP)**, **delegating tasks**, **and collaborating with team members** to achieve a shared vision.
- In one week, my team and I built the full stack app using the tech stack we had learnt. I explored multiple React packages and decided on using toast-ui/react-calendar and google forms.
- I also built a prototype for an iOS app using **React Native**.

ENGINEERING INTERN | BOARDPRO

09/2022 - 11/2022

 I contributed to the QA of the web app by performing regression and smoke testing, and documenting the outcomes in Jira. This culminated with an important version update where I tested the production environment to ensure a smooth deployment.

- I organised the team's documentation by learning their tech stack and archiving expired information. I extensively researched **agile methodologies** to write their team handbook.
- Through self-directed research, I completed a governance training course and learnt HTML5,
 CSS3 and JavaScript to build and present a CEO report form to go on the company's website.

ASSISTANT MANAGER | BED, BATH 'N TABLE REMUERA

10/2021 - 09/2022

• I managed a team of staff, oversaw stock control, and ensured that customers received exceptional service. I also had the opportunity to **utilise my visual design skills by creating visually appealing displays** following principles of interior design.

KITCHEN-HAND | DARUMA RAMEN COMMERCIAL BAY

06/2020 - 08/2021

 I had the opportunity to immerse myself in the world of Japanese cuisine and work in a dynamic, high-pressure kitchen environment. I developed valuable skills in time management, attention to detail, and the significance of working effectively in a team.

EDUCATION

DEV ACADEMY AOTEAROA | AUCKLAND, NZ

NZQA Level 6, Certificate of Applied Software Development 01/2023 - 05/2023

UNIVERSITY OF EDINBURGH | EDINBURGH, UK/REMOTE

BA History of Art 09/2018 - 04/2021

YONSEI UNIVERSITY SUMMER PROGRAM | SEOUL, KOR

East Asian History of Art & Korean language 07/2019 - 09/2019

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

My hobbies include, but are not limited to:

Gardening, archeology and ancient art history, painting, saxophone, macrame, hiking

References available on request